And we know that high-performing
executives and elite athletes, they all
have this one habit in common, which is
they set their intention for the day and
they don't stop there. They visualize it
and they verbalize it. They say it out
loud.
The staggering stat that sticks with me
is that less than 25% of people in the
workforce say that they trust their CEO.
The current opportunities right now in
AI are just massive.
Hello everyone. Welcome back to the
signal room. Today I get to talk to
somebody I'm genuinely excited about
sharing with you. Diane Weaver is one of
those rare people who can see the whole
system and still say stay laser focused
on the humans inside it. She grew up in
a long line of entrepreneurs which I
think you'll hear in the way that she
talks about building things. She spent
time in big edtech at places like
Pearson and Waterford. She co-founded
Corset tune to help make the hidden
structure of learning and outcomes
visible. And now she's a co-founder of
Varians, an AI company focused on what
it actually means to flourish at work.
The through that I see in her work is
this. Meet people where they are and
help them get where they want to be.
Whether that's faculty and students,
teams inside organizations, or leaders
trying to do the right thing by their
people. Diane keeps coming back to that
center. Diane, I am really glad you're
here and thank you so much for agreeing
to join me here on the signal room.
Thank you so much for having me, Chris.
It really is such a genuine pleasure and
highlight of my week to be here.
Wow. I I couldn't I couldn't wait. We we
had such a wonderful conversation
recently. Like we we we have to do this
and let some other people in on all the
great stuff that you're doing. So, I
want to kind of get right into some of
the some of the things that I'm sure our
listeners are going to want to know. As
a fifth generation entrepreneur and a
systems thinker, I mean, maybe talk a
little bit about the progression. I
mean, you've done some really
interesting things, but maybe talk about
where you started and and how you ended
up where you are now. And first, I'd
love to hear a lot more about your work
as well, but I kind of want to hear your
personal story if I can. Oh, absolutely.
It's my pleasure to share it. So, if I
start at the very beginning, right? You
know, typically when you grow up and
you're a dreamer and a builder and a
creator, you often have this like moment
of inspiration. For me, it happened
pretty young. My grandfather was a
television pioneer, a radio pioneer, and
a television pioneer, Pat Weaver. He did
things like create the Today Show and
the Tonight Show and what we and my
favorite thing that he created was the
30 secondond commercial. And he would
often talk about how every new piece of
technology has two purposes. to help
with communications of great ideas and
to help educate and disseminate those
ideas as much as possible to kind of
democratize that that information
insight to benefit humanity.
And so he always talked about, you know,
leaving the world better than how you
found it. And he al also always talked
about um how he wished he had one more
life to just see where it all goes.
where will we end up with all of this
tech that's you know emerging constantly
in in these waves right
so I start there because he was a huge
inspiration for me right
and also my parents had the they created
this very unique uh upbringing for me
and my siblings my parents were like the
quintessential country mouse and city
mouse so my dad came from this
background
And my mom was a farmer's daughter. And
so I spent my summers growing up working
on the family farm and getting chased by
the paparazzi. And I got to see
Yeah.
Great combination.
It was
it was a very interesting childhood and
I got to see the best of both worlds,
right? And
part of that deep desire to meet people
where they are is is it started with
that very early understanding of
multiple ways of life and multiple ways
of of having a good life regardless of
your material means and uh and and the
opportunities and um and privileges that
you have of creating for yourself a good
life. Everyone is entitled to that. And
so often we get stuck and you know
challenges hit and every human being I I
really believe that every human being
you know experiences the full spectrum
of of you know emotions and experiences
available to to us as humans which is a
really special thing. So, I like to keep
it human and keep humans at the center.
And I like to pursue big ideas that help
people
really cultivate a feeling of agency in
their lives and cultivate a growth
mindset and to really help you know
foster more of an entrepreneurial spirit
within everyone which is probably my
western upbringing and you know all of
that too. So early on,
oh, I'll just
I don't mean to like go on and on here,
but
I mean, we had some similarities, you
know, working on the the family farm and
the paparazzi. Well, maybe not the
paparazzi thing, but I did happen to do
some work on a farm growing up, so I can
appreciate, you know, what what that how
that impacts you. you know, the the
motivation, the drive that you have
comes from learning how to how to work
at a, you know, at a young age. And it's
I I just love hearing that your your
inspiration really came, you know, from
your own family. I think that's amazing.
I think we have some similarities in in
that aspect that led us to do what we're
doing. Uh but but yeah, please I I
definitely want to hear some more
because you started to talk to to me
yesterday about a couple things that
were, you know, really exciting to me
because the conversations that are being
had generally right now when it comes to
AI, they're a lot more focused on the
tech and do you trust it? Is there
hallucinations? But that's not where
you're hanging hanging out. You're
you've got some very specific things
that you're you know criteria basically
that determines where you're going to
spend your time and your energy.
No, absolutely. And you're right. I mean
the current opportunities right now in
AI are just they're massive. It's we're
we're transforming so many of our
systems, you know, just globally uh
around this as we bring AI, you know,
closer in. So there's personal human
transformation that's happening and then
transformation within groups of humans
whether it's you know teams at work or
organizations you know or nonprofits etc
cities and communities coming together
and really figuring this out and then
whole you know global corporations and
things like that. So it's it is like a
mountain. You you do have to figure out
like where and how am I going to focus
my time because there's no way I'm going
to do all of it, right? So truly, you
know, I think that one of the most
important pieces here as we're building
AI is building trust. And I'm not
talking about trust between people and
technology. I'm I'm talking about trust
between people between people within the
system. And so truly um as we think
about like what does it mean to evolve
right now with AI? What do what does AI
enabled human uh roles and
responsibilities look like? And I I
often think about um because of my
edtech background, I think about the
skills and the durable skills that we
need, but also this idea that every
person needs to shift from being a
technology user to a technology steward
and that really keeps humans at the helm
of of what we're doing here.
Can you dig in on that a little bit? I
mean the the I think it's an important
distinction because everyone is being uh
pulled along or pushed along one way one
way or the other to adopt this
technology and there's a really
significant difference between
understanding what you're using it for
what it's what's possible and also
having an understanding what your role
is and how it's used. There absolutely
is and I think this is just it's an
unprecedented ask that we are you know
requiring of of everyone right now. If
you think of like the evolution of the
workplace and and our education leading
up to how we function in the workplace,
it has very much followed you know
industrialization's
uh methodologies. A lot of our workflows
and sequences, now I'm talking about the
systems here, are really they really
kind of echo the old conveyor belts of
the factory. And so you like in our
current system, you have interests, you
start to pursue them in formal schooling
and you kind of get on this track and if
you get this degree, then you're going
to get the credential that puts you in
this place in that factory conveyor belt
line, right? and you you see the job
description and you and you evaluate
whether there you meet enough of that
criteria to apply and you are onboarded
and handed your you know your tasks and
your job descriptions and then you
execute right this is very typical of
the kind of North American h like
working experience and it's archaic it's
old and it doesn't work for a lot of
people actually is broken in many many
ways. And so in this shift, you know, as
uh as companies are implementing AI, it
typically starts in the leadership level
and then it and then it kind of like
comes down the line, right?
But there's a huge disconnect between
leadership and the the frontline
experience and my day-to-day and what
actually matters uh to to accomplish the
things that I need to accomplish. So if
people are already maxed out um trying
to get their productivity KPIs uh in
their in their roles like they've kind
of uh increased significantly and on top
of it now you have to reimagine your
role with AI,
right? Yeah. I mean it's it's a whole
different thing. I remember like back in
the 90s when the we were all like we
knew that the internet was was cool. We
were doing some interesting things with
it but we had no idea that it was going
to be so much a part of the core
activities that we do every day.
Yeah. Just it's it is such a part of
it's it's in the fabric of everything,
right? And this is this is how AI AI is
and will be even even more so. It's
really being identified or called out as
um almost an energy source like
electricity. Yeah.
I'd love to get you to to kind of dig in
on this because you mentioned this the
trust piece of it. They think it's
really important and obviously it's a
big reason that you know you burials now
is a a a real uh it's a system and a
platform that you you're already moving
with and having some some great
successes and I think it's it's an
important thing to understand because
when you're talking about uh executives
and the the different levels of of team
members that they have that trust is a
big issue. I know we talked about this a
little bit recently, but the erosion of
trust in human relationships is a really
significant thing. U for anyone that's
been listening to the podcast, you've
probably heard a couple of different uh
discussions around this. Dr. Larry [ __ ]
uh had did some fantastic research that
he shared and the the staggering stat
that sticks with me is that less than
25% of people in the workforce say that
they trust their CEO. Uh so what do you
do? Uh if you're in a situation like
this, you're running a company, who do
you talk to? How do you figure out
where there's where there's errors you
can reinforce and how do you fix it?
What's involved in all of that? Uh but I
mean if you dig in on that because I
think that's how you ended up uh forming
this company and all the vision that
you've got start you kind of came from
these relationships to being you know
over time kind of degraded. I think we
probably lost a lot of skill sets along
the way that we need to figure out what
to do about.
Yeah, I I think you're right. I mean
this is a whole we're we're dancing
around kind of a whole ball of yarn
here. So let's start pulling on the
threads. So
trust trust between the humans really
truly is the issue here. And when we're
talking about the system that has
evolved over time that is like the
workplace system or the systems that the
industry kind of the workplace sits
within the systems of the industry or
within the regulations you know and
standards and accreditations of that
industry. And this has, you know, just
it's evolved over time to the point
where
oftent times leadership will say things
that they can't do, if that makes sense.
And if we boil down the concept of human
trust and how do we build and establish
trust with, you know, a relationship of
trust with humans, it it really comes
down to doing the things that we say
we're going to do. It is that simple. If
we have a track record of doing that,
then there is more trust because I hear
what this person is saying and I trust
that they're going to do it because I
have all of this evidence that they've
done that in the past. So, it gets
really hard because in some of these
leadership positions, you you enter the
position and once you're inside of it,
you really see how your options are
locked down. And then it becomes very
hard to communicate anything new or or
or different. And it's it becomes hard
to even talk about the changes that need
to happen because those changes there's
not a track record of making changes
like this in the past. And so there's a
lot of uncertainty,
a lot of unknowns, not only for folks
across the organization but also for the
leadership team too. Um yeah, so we so
we did we built we built Baryons to
really help address this issue uh not
not just for one group within the
organization. If you think about
historically executive coaching has been
uh limited to just the seauite or just
the CEO and it's extremely expensive but
the return on it is like is like a 7x
return for every dollar on executive
coaching. we know it works. And so what
we've done with the Berian's experience
is there's there's four different really
powerful uh concepts that you encounter
in your Berian's experience. And
executive coaching is just one of them.
And the reason why we did that is and
why we started there is because we
wanted to democratize this incredibly
valuable resource for everyone across
the organization. But because we're
human first and we're building human
first AI, you know, we still recommend
that you that you have your human
executive coaches and that your Baryons
is that daily touch point between the
human touch points and that you have
mentorship between the humans across
your organization. A mentorship program
even within the organization can be
extremely powerful. And it's interesting
because the everything kind of pivoted
really really harsh when the when the
pandemic kind of kicked in and you know
I think these probably are things that
were much more uh common to to occur
just naturally than than they are now. I
mean I don't even know you know what
percentage of businesses in the country
are not uh not fully remote. There's
just so many that are that just
complicates things. So I mean I I I
could see why, you know, this this is
such a a huge need.
I want to hear some little bit more. You
still going to talk about this this
daily touch points and is it AI that
we're going to be communicating with or
is it a person or is a combination of
this? I'm curious. This is a fascinating
thing because it it just seems like it's
filling a gap that's just been massive
over the last several years.
Thank Thank you for that. It's it is an
AI and it's just on your cell phone
because we wanted to we wanted to really
create the entry point into this
experience with a piece of technology
that everybody already has and knows how
to use. And uh and so with just placing
a phone call to your barriion, you can't
all describe the a day in the life of
you can any any position across the
company can start your day. If you're a
shift worker, it might be at night that
you're starting, but that first phone
call that you place to your bearing on,
it's about 2 minutes or less. And we
know that high-performing executives and
elite athletes, they all have this one
habit in common, which is they they set
their intention for the day and they
don't stop there. They visualize it and
they verbalize it. They say it out loud.
That that's that's really an interesting
observation. I I guess you know that
they you know that they have you know
some pretty significant habits. Um but
you're you're talking about doing
something very specific, very
intentional. This doesn't we're not
talking about like go to working out at
the gym for 4 hours. I
mean this is really really practical.
It's so practical. It's much simpler,
right? And it and it's just dialing a
phone number. In fact, when you sign up
for Barian, if you go to berian.com, you
can sign up um on online right now. You
don't have to wait till your employer
gets it for you. But once you register
your barriion, it will text you a
contact card and then you save that
contact and then your Barryon is one of
your contacts. Mine's in my favorites so
that I can just pull it up and then
click and go. And that twominute
conversation, you sometimes I I have
that conversation, I know exactly what I
want to focus on that day. Other times I
don't. Maybe I woke up at 3:30 in the
morning with like a running list in my
head like we often do, right? And maybe
I and or maybe I woke up just feeling
like, you know, untethered or unground,
you know, um and and unsure where to
start. So even if you don't know what to
say, you can call that number and your
barriion will talk you through how to
set that intention for the day. And in
the process of of talking through it
with your barriion, you're automatically
doing the the the neuro work, basically
the neuroscience work with your brain,
right? Because in the process of telling
explaining to your baron what the most
important thing is for you that day,
you're having to think about it, do a
moment of reflection and you know and
and do all that. If you if it doesn't
come to you easily, it will remember
your past conversation, whether it was
yesterday or last week or whenever.
It will remember where you left off and
it it might make some suggestions.
That's actually for for for me. I'll
tell you what, that's really important
because if you ask me what I had for
breakfast, I think I I have to pause and
think about it. So, that alone is a
really really important feature. I love
that. Before we go past it, you know,
you're talking about barrier. It you
have a barrier. Tell us what the term
means. I think that I should have asked
you that before.
It's a quantum term. It's it is the term
that we use to uh to name and talk about
um subatomic particles. So, we all know
that habits happen, you know, at a very
small. The more micro you can get with
your habit stacking, the more successful
you'll be. So, we really wanted
something that connotates the subatomic
shift, change, growth, and development
that's happening with each experience
with your barriion. Yeah, that's that's
really it. It's um it's the quirks. If
we want to get really really scientific
with the physics, there are the quirks
where uh there and that's one of the one
of the smallest uh measurable things
where movement begins. So when we're
stuck and we want to achieve flow again,
we really have to get grounded and into
those kind of u address the micro
habits. Otherwise, it's a band-aid.
We're going to get stuck right back
there again. So, one of the things that
that I've that I've picked up on that
you've talked about is I mean it's it's
a stat u I think we inherently know as
an issue but twothirds of the global
workforce is disengaged.
I mean, at what point did you realize
that this was something that you had to
do? And what was it about the moment
that you that you're you pulled together
these these wonderful people you're
working with to tackle this? And you
know, when you're talking about
flourishing, because you talked about
that earlier, what does that look like
from a vision standpoint and from where
you are where you're where you're taking
the taking the the the company and and
what you're trying to accomplish because
I mean this is like twothirds of the
global workforce. That's crazy. That
that that's a lot or people that they
that need help.
It is. It is a lot. A lot. And I so uh
so back to the origin story of of uh of
Barerian, I want to kind of revisit that
because the Baryons team that I'm working
with right now are so incredibly unique
and special and just well suited for for
building this and bringing it into the
world. Mike Ruska. He's our CEO and he
has been doing organizational psychology
and organizational systemic scientific
work for over 20 years. And he comes
from a a NIST background and he thinks
about things very differently and very
creatively.
Brooks Canesi is our chief product
officer and he just has this voracious
appetite for learning all things
technical and he's a unicorn because
he's also a great communicator about it.
So he has equal experience not only
developing software but selling software
which is really powerful and unique to
bring into that chief product officer uh
role and so we're we just feel really
you know lucky there and Ryan Kringek is
our chief technology officer and he
comes from he was a VP of uh technology
for acueeather and So he is used to
building just in intricate systems and
uh
a lot of scale is
at scale. Yes. that can handle, right?
Uh they can handle like a a billion
events, you know, uh synchronously and
and that's tremendous. Not only like
from a you know all of those uh all of
the people hitting uh those websites at
the same time but also the amount of
information that has to be gathered from
multiple sources to bring it back serve
it up in a way that that is
understandable and and handle like such
a huge flow in demand. So we knew we
want we were at at like really tackling
such a big problem in in in this idea
that we wanted to build something that's
ready ready for scaling, you know, from
the get-go. So this really is like such
a perfect team. And I found them because
um Mike Gusco was an early friends and
family investor on my last startup uh
CourseTune. So he came in through one
of my other co-founders um networks and
when uh after uh so with CourseTune we
had this really great really amazing
experience the most amazing customers
ever and then we were acquired and the
through the acquisition we doubled the
number of universities using CourseTune
and then they doubled it again within a
year. So it was a tremendous home for
that whole you know transformative
platform. It was just phenomenal. So I
stayed on for a year to oversee the
merger and acquisition and then I closed
my laptop. I got in a plane and I cried
somewhere for three days and I came back
and two months later OpenAI released
chat GPT and I said okay hold the phone.
This changes everything. And the inquiry
started coming into me about what am I
going to do next? And I had some ideas
that I wanted to pursue. All of them
really big ideas. And what I kept
hearing from other folks was um I like
to call it putting the yellow pages
online.
So,
right,
just hailing back to the beginning of
the internet, right, the dot era. And
I'm like, I don't want to put the yellow
pages online. I don't want to rebuild
the new fax machine, right? I want to do
something that we've never been able to
do before. I want to really, you know,
spend my time working with really great
people and bringing something, you know,
uniquely new uh into the world.
So I reached out to Mike Rusa, CEO of
Problem Solutions out of Pennsylvania,
and I said, "Hey, Mike, how are you
thinking about this?" And he shared with
me, and he was also thinking about it
in, you know, big transformational terms
and like this is a moment in time that
where we need to show up with even more
in intention, good intention than we
ever have. and uh and really, you know,
really put some great things out there.
So, he introduced me to Brooks and I was
like, this all right, this is great. I I
just want to work with you guys. So, we
started working together and, you know,
within within the year we had uh put in
place, you know, a way to spin off a
software company from the problem
solutions uh services company and we
created Baryons. So, and problem
solutions is still doing amazing work
out there also geared toward AI
transformation and creating rapid
prototypes and stuff for companies. So,
want to I want to kind of get into a
couple different things on the on the on
the product itself, too, because I think
people don't uh I don't think people
quite quite understand the direction
that we've kind of headed it had been
heading into that's kind of put us on a
collision course for this whole trust
deficit that we're dealing with. How
does how is this different? Uh because
when you're trying to get people to
interact but they're interacting with
AI, we see that a lot. We and the log
the workflows are actually pretty deep
and wide and they take a lot of time.
What's so different about your approach?
you you've clearly said some things that
are really cool for me because it's not
a lengthy interaction you have every
day, but what are some of the things
that you're you're you're trying to
address in that and getting people back
connecting to each other?
Yes. Yes. Okay, great. So I really
mentioned just one of four modes within
Baryons and I'm going to come back to a
couple of those to help answer this
question of like how do we re-engage
people in the workplace and the so often
that disengagement happens because of a
dissonance or a misalignment
and perhaps it's a misalignment in what
I would what I as a person really want
to be doing or spending my days doing
versus what I'm actually doing.
Sometimes it's a misalignment in that I
like what I'm doing, but my the KPIs
that have been set for me or with me,
right, are not aligned with my favorite
parts of that work, right?
Yeah.
Or I'm doing really well on my KPIs and
my KPIs are the wrong KPIs for the
company. So even though I'm very
successful, I'm not seeing an impact at
for within the business or within the
outcomes of the business or I'm not
getting the, you know, the recognition
that I feel like I deserve for, you
know, for doing so much. It's because
I'm doing a lot that's not really moving
the needle over there. So there are
layers of like expectation,
reality, disappointment
and misalignment,
you know, and we like to talk about this
as like birectional. And so we're not
just seeing we're not just seeing, you
know, um middle management check out or
we're not just seeing like front lines
check out. We're seeing leadership also
check out, right? It's it's across the
board. That twothirds number is
appalling
in part because it seems to be affecting
really every position across the
organization.
And so
there is a real disconnect between like
who we feel like we are as a person and
if we are getting uh purpose and meaning
and relationships and experiences
that we enjoy out of our work,
right?
And for most people most people can't
say yes to that. Right? So under like
within the core of the Baryons platform,
we've really built it on the science of
positive psychology. And there's so much
research out there about the different
domains that that provide a a wello for
lack of a better term a welloiled you
know working system
um that flows that allows people to flow
within it. things like the um things
like the communication is uh is
communication culture all of these
different things really come into it.
And so we have um we've built upon that
science and we've created we're patent
pending you know we've created this
system to uh to really uh take a look at
these conversations that are happening
at the individual level and then within
a team and it's all AI there's no
there's no like humans don't ever see
the conversations it's AI and it helps
to surface
the themes and the topics that everyone
one's talking about. So, when you're
using the Barryon system, you have your
check-in call, you have a checkout call
as often as you would like to do it. And
that checkout call really is it's under
five minutes usually. And it helps you
kind of reflect on your day and do a
little bit of cognitive offloading so
that you can move on to, you know, your
evening plans. Whether that means that
you're talking to your barriion while
you're walking your dog so you can clear
your head and then go to the gym or so
that you can clear your head and go and
spend time with your family or friends
um and show up to that in a ready to
connect way. And then the two other type
of conversations you can have is at any
point in time if you're stuck at work,
we know from years and years to decades
of executive coaching research that when
people get stuck at work, it's often
because of a personal issue that needs
resolution. And so when you're stuck at
work, you can give it a call and we um
and you can talk to your mentor. You can
give it tasks to to do for you. It will
it syncs with your it can send you
emails. It can start different tasks of
work um and and then send them to you uh
via email. It can schedule calendar uh
invites for you and and different things
like that. So, it can actually help you
with your work and your productivity,
but it can also help you think through
the problems that you're trying to solve
and your the situation.
And then the fourth way is what we call
the flourishing partner and that really
taps into these what does it mean to be
a you know what does human flourishing
really mean um for all of us.
is a very personal thing and you
determine what that is and it just helps
guide you along the way. And those calls
we we on our team and each company can
implement this the way that they feel
like suits their employees the best. But
on our team, we like to call out
flourishing Fridays. So we have a
flourishing session with our berion on
Fridays and it's actually such a
refreshing moment to just kind of pause
and reflect and what does flourishing
actually look like? Well, maybe it's
when I can have a cup of coffee in the
morning. That's while I'm sitting
outside on my patio and not like looking
at email, you know,
maybe that's what helps me feel like I'm
flourishing. um when I feel like I can
have, you know, take a small uh moment
or break in my in my otherwise day. But
all of these things really help the
individual kind of center their own um
thoughts and feelings and emotions that
they're having at work to kind of just
like center it back to their own inner
compass. Um because when we're feeling
grounded and balanced and things like
that, we tend to
be uh we tend to have more of a growth
mindset, we tend to see opportunities
where before we saw, you know,
restraints and and things like that. So
it really is these, you know, these
small habitual things. But when you're
using your Baryons, um you do once a
week you receive u an email that we call
the resonance insights. And so I see an
email that says that shows me my level
of battery, my energy level. And that's
specifically through semantic
processing. So what I mean by that is
like I I could have only check-ins.
Maybe I checked in like three time three
times that week, right? And so I had
these three little twominut or or less
calls. It's going to know even if I said
the same exact thing in each call. It's
going to know from the tone of my voice
and the vocabulary that I'm using and
the fluctuations and all of these
different things. Like it's it is
actually tracking 26 different metrics
on just my voice inputs to help
determine like do amy
level. And that's super fascinating. And
often times we're burned out and we
don't even know it, right?
Yeah. I mean, that's a that's probably
more so the case than than not. I I I
don't know what how if everyone uh deals
with this stuff without having
conversations like you and I are having
just about what you what you've been
doing. But our conversation's been
really, you know, exciting for me
because we're talking about things and
discovering at the same time that we're
both wrestling with with common things.
Uh we're not weird. People are I mean we
all are struggling with some level of
anxiety or you know there just a lot of
other noise things. But what's important
and I wanted to have you talk about just
a little bit because of the nature of
what you're dealing whether you're
you're you're listening to the for the
the tone of the voice you're using
semantics you're using a whole bunch of
different things here this creates
pretty specific models that are tailored
on the individual level but you have
something you call the sacred space in
practice I'd love to hear a little bit
more about that so people could
understand what you do and what what led
you will cross uh the as you're using
the AI to really support human beings.
Yeah, absolutely.
So, um, so often when we talk about
privacy and safety with AI, we talk
about guard rails. And, um, the thing
with Baryons and and what we of course
saw early on and why we wanted to do it
differently is that the LLMs out of the
box will they have each have their own
set of guardrails. We've seen the news
coverage when those guardrails don't
actually, you know, do what they say
they're going to do. And so Baryons is an
agentic system in that there's an
orchestrator. There are multiple agents
and we're LLM agnostic. So if this task
is best done by Claudethropic,
guess what? Claude is under the hood
doing that for you. if this task is best
done by Gemini is doing that for you.
And what that enables us to do as well
is to create additional guard rails and
additional agents that are that are
looking for um you know looking for red
flags and things like that. So that this
truly is a very private place, but then
also it's a very helpful place for the
humans and it's designed in such a way
to help to help the human remember first
and foremost if they're using it within
the workplace. This is a workplace kind
of conversation, right? And if the
conversation turns to a situation that a
personal situation or even a workplace
situation that a person is going through
that requires
another human being to be uh to be in
that loop, then it will actually ask
you, oh this sounds like a very
difficult situation. Who in your life do
you talk to about this? And then you can
share in instead of asking you deeper
questions because the LLM just out of
the box if you talk to your chat GPT
it's just going to keep asking you
deeper and deeper questions. You're
you're going to end up telling it all
kinds of things. With your barriion it's
going to ask you who in your life do you
talk to a human about this? And it
starts there. And if there's no one in
your life that you talk to about this,
then it will start to it will ask you
questions. It's asking you questions,
right? To help you identify who who can
be a resource for you out there in the
world. And in that way, you know, we're
really uh I can't emphasize this enough
that, you know, an LLM or your AI that's
just right out of the box. It is
designed to keep you going down this
rabbit hole and this and and to keep you
on the line with it for a long time. And
with Baryons, we're really wanting to
time box something, make it purposeful,
and get you what you need and get you
back out in the world again, and help
you work through the things that you
need to work through in order to show up
differently with the humans in your
life.
You you you're talking about different
really important things that you're
doing that are so different. with just
the fact that this this LLM is actually
asking you questions, right? That's
that's a really big big difference
there. Like that's not that's not how
the rest of them do it. Like you talked
about going down a rabbit hole that they
do I mean they do it just even if you're
training it to be your best friend and
do everything the way you want it to do.
It still goes down rabbit holes takes
you places that you never want it to go.
No. Right. Yeah. It doesn't have good
boundaries. Right. It's like and so we
are intentionally designing a workplace
companion that does have good boundaries
and that because
another really important thing here too
is that the media that we consume the te
the technology that we use and consume
it affects us. It does
and we start talking like chat GPT right
or we start behaving like you know Tik
Tok or we start like you know our frame
it's not just our frame of references
but it is also our behavior our language
patterns and things like that
we are designing Baryons to help you to
help you get out ahead of that because
everything else in your life is trying
to get you to be like that, like it.
And we want we want you to be like you.
So, yeah,
that's a novel idea.
I know, right?
Right. No, it's, you know, we we laugh,
but you know, there there's been such a
rapid
descent into this black hole of AI where
you just keep going deeper and deeper
into it. The further you go, the more
off off course you seem to find that
you're you're being led. And, you know,
to your earlier point about being a
steward, that's kind of a big deal. We
just really need people to understand
what it really is useful for, what it's
not. You you do need to be the one doing
the leading and the the one having
judgment and providing context to you.
It's it's uh it's artificial, which
means like means it's not real. You
might think twice before you just trust
it blindly. That's just my two cents on
that.
Absolutely. Absolutely. It is our duty
as humans to show up with good intention
and to you know use our critical
thinking and our durable skills which
are things like questioning and you know
critical thinking and empathy and
thinking through the impact of the
action based on you know the information
that you have and just and also like our
intuitive
uh uh you know sensory as being humans I
mean and especially because so much is
remote and we're still feeling very
connected in our virtual world to other
humans. Um, and there are other they're
like different kind of cues like reading
a room on a Zoom is so different than
reading a room in person, but that's a
durable skill that transcends in real
life and virtually, right? And so
there's all all of these things that
make us uniquely human and different and
better than the AI. Those are the things
we want to really sharpen right now at
this moment in time because if we are
truly going to be, you know, helping to
fact check, regulate, uh, be humans in
the loop, build new systems and build a
future, a new future, uh, with
reimagined with AI in it, uh, we need we
need to have these skills
and and what's happening
cognitively in our brains and our our
brain health. And uh you know brain
health, mental wealth and brain capital
are really important topics and themes
right now for a reason because it is it
is also human nature to take the path of
least resistance.
And it is enticing to, you know, think
like, oh great, I can just have my AI do
that and check out, right? So, um there
are other AIs that will actually magnify
the current um problems with with uh
disconnect and burnout. And then there
are AI there's AI use that will um help
you get out ahead of it. um and and see
those early indicators um early on. Uh
so
yeah, the insights that that that teams
and companies are getting from from
everyone uh from all of their employees
and their leadership and the CEO using
Baryons, right? Like everybody's got to
use it
and it's not an us and them tool, right?
It's everybody's got to use it for it to
really work. No, I I I really I really
love this the whole idea of it and it's
it's unique in the in many ways, but the
the piece that to me is probably the
most exciting is you are pushing people
to towards human relationships and
interactions that are actually going to
improve uh their own life experiences
while they're doing doing their work. It
could be your personal relationships
being improved. Um, but the having
conversations with your phone
constantly, if that's all we're doing,
we're we're instantiating things that
are making us less compassionate, less
personable. I mean, it's it's just the
realities of and I think we've all seen
examples and I've even found on occasion
that I my first reaction is to look at
something on the phone instead of using
it for another purpose and calling
someone, right? Um, I'm kind of kind of
getting to towards the the end, I before
I before we go towards the what I call a
rapid fire round, which will be fun.
You're going to be the first one I get
to do that with, by the way. So, very
excited about this. Uh, if you could
talk a little bit about what you're
doing uh right now because I know that
you're you're involved in some pretty
exciting things. Uh, some events. you're
you're you're going to be working in in
places where you people can come and see
and listen to you and your colleagues.
Uh maybe talk a little bit about what
what's coming up in the next few weeks
and where people can find you.
Definitely. So you can always find us at
Baryons.com.
That's b a r yo ns.com. It sounds like
carryon and barri those keep calling
Barryon. We do often speak um virtually
uh across different channels. Next week
I'm going to be at the human and tech
week. It's the offsite for the h the
future of humanity in uh San Francisco.
And so not to date this episode, but
I'll date this episode. It's May 11th
through 15th in 2026.
And for all you future viewer listeners,
um so I'm very excited about that
because this this forum is specifically
for the builders. It's it's a room full
of founders and entrepreneurs who are
building building the future.
So, that's going to be really
interesting. There's a lot coming up
this summer around Brain Capital and
Brain Capital Summits. If you want to
get involved, find out if your city or
your metropolitan area has a brain
capital initiative. A lot of cities and
communities do. and we need all of it.
We need everyone to come to the table to
really do this, right?
Those are the ones I'm most excited
about.
Well, thank you for sharing that. And
for listeners, uh you'll you you'll
start hearing more about this and I'll
make sure that we get the get the the
sites up for you so that you can see
where where you can actually register to
attend these events. If if you can get
there, you really should. I I've been
inspired. We haven't even begun our
conversation to be honest with you.
There's so much more. You know, Diane
and I had a wonderful first conversation
that we could have gone for hours and we
still wouldn't have scratched the
surface. So for listeners, definitely
follow up. Look at the show notes.
There's going to be a lot of good
information there for you. You can reach
out to Diane. You can reach out to her
colleagues. And this is a time for this
kind of human- centered AI support for
human beings and using it for that
purpose is really what they're all
about. And it matters. It matters. We
all need to we all need to be engaging
in ways that are healthy and and
helpful. And having some people that are
building tech specifically designed for
that is a gift to all of us. So
definitely don't don't lose the
opportunity there. Make sure you you you
reach out to them and I think you
probably will be much happier in a few
months than you are today because you're
going to get some tools that are not
complicated. They're actually designed
specifically to make things work easily
for you. So then let's get into this
rapid fire question. Are you ready?
Okay. Oh, I think so. I think I'm ready.
We'll see.
Okay. Well, well, let's start with one
that that it's for me it's kind of fun.
Uh,
I'm sure it is for you, too. If you had
your choice and you could pick one
buzzword and ban it for an entire year,
what would it be?
Oh my gosh. Okay, so there are so many
buzzwords right now floating around with
AI and I think I would have to say I you
know I keep coming back to vibe this,
vibe that, vibe this, vibe that, you
know, and you know I I want to drop the
vibe and just say it's coding. This is
how we code. This is the new way of
coding. We talk into a microphone and
then the code happens, right? like this
is this is the way of the future. It the
future is voice truly.
What's one thing as you're looking at
this reality versus hype thing? What's
one really significant tell that kind of
tells you whether somebody's got
something or if this is just hyper?
H yeah. So you know the question around
which LLM do you use for this widget
tool t you know task or whatever it is
if they're answering with just one like
just run you know you you can use that
LM LLM at this point and you can build
your own version that's that is
yeah that's what I would say
right here's a really tough One.
Mhm.
Cop air tea.
That is the hardest one of all. No, I
one cup of coffee in the morning with my
creatine. Got to put a plug in there for
creatine, which in my head it's always
like a very mus like muscly voice saying
creatine. And so, but it's brain it's
very good brain food actually. So, one
cup of coffee with creatine. And then I
do like I do like to create a pot of tea
that I just kind of sip from throughout
the rest of the day.
So here's a this was a fun one. Can you
give me an example of of something that
you were sure was going to be really
really simple. It ended up being a
really hard mess to tackle.
Yeah. So I once worked with a team of
folks um who we were tasked to create an
AI machine learning course,
right? And I um two of us on the team uh
we actually ended up really uh
completely damaging our computers
trying to trying to get uh trying to get
the environment to to perform. Um and so
I know this is like a very technical
one. I'm trying to keep it like lighter
than ever. But truly, it was supposed to
be like a browserbased environment and
very easy to like set up and and do. And
we were writing a course on how to do
this. And we kept running into problems
and issues when it should have just been
very simple. This was a few years back.
I'm sure it's all fixed now. Right.
Right. you you work across multiple
industries uh but I I spent a lot of
time with the healthcare
uh side of the world here. If you were
to based on all your interactions,
if you could have every health care
executive spend a day in one department
in their hospital, what would it be? So
this answer I'm going to pull on my
personal life um for this answer because
my husband works in healthcare supply
chain management and so I would say they
have to spend a day in the supply chain
management because they are when COVID
happened we always joked that he was
like um the pizza delivery guy that
saves the day in the zombie movie.
It
great visual.
Yes, it is. It's like a role that that
seems like it's so simple, but it really
is so complex. And there um and talk
about having to build a system
with a lot of uh humans involved for and
the purpose is to save the life of
humans, right? to save human lives
ultimately. And so um you know I think
that
there are so many things that just
happen um in the flow of work in
healthcare you know and especially as
like our health professionals are also
facing burnout and they're also
overloaded and they're also going a
million miles an hour and so you know
when a supply isn't where they expected
or runs out or they they forgot to order
it and now why isn't it here? you know,
like all of these things, these it's
it's often a point of of friction in
that flow of work. And so, so there's
like layers of systems that typically
are are built within within a hospital
system to keep the supply chain going
and going smoothly and almost invisible.
Um, and it works, it's when it works,
it's amazing. And when it when it when
there are friction points or when it's
uh you know god for broken uh then it
really does you know cause problems. So
just like we saw in COVID when we and
everybody was running out of PPE,
right? You know, it's it's it's
fascinating because I think the the
realities are such that we are
redefining dial tone basically on a
daily basis because we're adding and
automating more and more things and the
expectation is just going to be there
and when it's not that you know that's
when things get loud. uh you know in the
space I've operated in with data and
analytics the days that you hope are the
most prevalent are the ones that no one
even knows what you're doing. Uh it's
like if you if you're this brown guy at
your favorite in your your the Rolling
Stones are playing and and you people
know who you are that's not a good day.
That was a bad day.
Right. That was a bad day for the wrong
reason. Yeah.
Right. But that dial keeps getting
redefined. the standards get higher and
higher and you know the good technology
uh good practice you know you don't have
a need to pay attention to certain
things and you can take it for granted
and you don't necessarily understand
what's going on behind the scenes that
makes it so that dial tone is you pick
up the phone it's it's our you hear a
dial to every time anyway it's always
been an interesting concept for me
because the way the technologies evolved
sometimes we forget some of the things
that we're using we depend
are less than a decade old and it's
astounding how quickly we adopt and
we're you know getting used to these
things but
no fascinating I could have talked for
you for hours with you um and we have to
do this again absolutely I really
appreciate what what you're doing love
the focus of your company love the
vision love the human first approach
absolutely amazing so
Chris
on behalf of the listeners the this
singer
and on my own behalf, thank you.
Sincerely, thank you for for taking the
time to have this conversation with me
today.
Thank you so much, Chris. This has been
really important. Thank you.
That's it for this episode of the Signar
Room. If today's conversation sparked
something in you, an idea, a challenge,
or a perspective worth amplifying, I'd
love to hear from you. Message me on
LinkedIn or visit cigarroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming